Ladies and gentlemen, good evening.
We are at the Central Hotel in
Athens, the
Intelligent and Security Forum conference has just ended.  Well, I'm
here with a man who has an
extraordinary interest.  Many of you
know him.  It's Ton Kyriakou.
He is a former executive of the
United States Central Intelligence Agency
, i.e. the CIA.  He is one
of the most talked about agents
in the world for the
various cases he
has taken on.  He was here today
at the conference to speak
about issues
related to cybersecurity,
issues related to
intelligence services and
intelligence operations.   You
are Kyriakou.  Mr. Kyriakou, good evening
.  Good evening.
Hey, thank you very much for agreeing to
speak to Zunglagr.  Thank you very
much.  Thank you.  Well, I will ask the
questions in Greek and Mr.
Kyriakou, because he is of Greek
origin, will answer us in English
and you will see the
translation more easily below.  Yes.  So, let's
start.
From your experience, what do
you think has
changed in the secret services in
recent
years?
Most
international services, including Russia and China,
are seen more and
more as what we call the 800 gorilla in
the room
.  So, what do you think is the
most
effective secret service
on the planet right now, in your opinion
and in your experience?  Okay, don't
tell me the CIA.  No.
Israel
isleion Israel operation
upones they blew upers and killed many
people this was a
war and I said Yeah, it was probably a
war crime, but from an intelligence
point of view, it was brilliant.  Think
about the work that was involved in
something like this.  They had to control
the manufacturing of the devices.  They
had to control the supply chain of the
devices and then they had to get the
devices into the hands of the people
that they wanted to
kill incredibly.  And they did it.  They
succeeded.  I think they're the best in the
world.  M. I want to come to ours a little bit
, because you have experience and you have
information from the
time you were in the CIA
and now, of course, you collaborate with
many, many
intelligence officers around the world.  How
likely is it in your opinion that an
episode, a heated episode between Greece
and Turkey, so in line with
your experience, and in which and in
such an
eventuality, what stance do you think
the United States would take?
Gre all worons number tury is
soer
moreigeranten is
even worry for second reason that we
can't trust the unit states to come in
on the side of
gre think unit states to be honest
broker
in
cases
needates on
grey
expism
trust no matter who do
you think that in a case of a
military conflict between Greece and Turkey,
our country here Greece will be alone.   He
will have no allies.
I think Greece has the strong support of
NATO but espcially the Italians, the
French the
German British countries that have
relations in the first place turkey and
the borders are there no changing the
Turks can't just take islands or take
territory not acceptable so I think that
even without American leadership Greece
would be okay would be Okay.  So in
a conflict, do you believe that Greece will
stand up to Turkey just fine?
They are doing well militarily at the moment.
Okay.  Well, there is something you
know from your tenure here
in Greece that would be interesting to
share with us.  I'm not talking about
business, but something you wanted to
share with the world
who sees us for our country.
How long were you here during
your tenure here?
skilled people
economy transformed itself in one
generation
and they've just attracted business
from the biggest companies on the planet
a healthy economy a safe place
to if I have children still at home
Would you live here.  Yes.  Interesting.  Now, I'm going to take
you to something else and I
would really like you to answer
this question because I'm sure that
many who are in the
services are watching this
interview.  What is the difference, in
your opinion, between the new
secret service executives, that is, the new
agents who are now entering the market,
compared to the agents of
your own era?  Oh, where I was you were doing
your own business.  What is the
difference between the new agents compared to
your era? What do you think
has
changed things?  Two.  Yes.  Number one, it
is much harder to be an intelligence
officer today than it was when I was in
the CIA.  And it's because of the
development of technology especially AI
and facial recognition software.  I don't
know how people cross borders now.  I had
six different passports.  How do they
cross borders when everything is
scanned and saved?  Number one.  Number
two, the advice that I would give is
don't let technology take over
your job.  The job of intelligence
officer
spies NSA
to come to our own
secret services here in Greece and
end it with this.  I would like to
ask you, in your opinion, how autonomous
our own secret services are today
.  That is, the National
Intelligence Service, because that's what it's called now.  Well,
from your experience, how autonomous
can it be and if you would like to
characterize it that way, but
describe to us a little about its operational
capabilities, always according to
your experience.  That is, we have a
national intelligence service that
is good at the operational level
relative to other services in the world.
Is it effective or does it need a lot of
work? Still, in your opinion, it always
needs work.
Mmm.
Grey, need more personnel.  They need
more training and they need more
specialization.
You can have a lot of people working on
Turkey.  You can't have everybody working
on Turkey, right?  You
have you have to have enough money to
hlectors to collect the information and
analyze to analyze the information and write
the information for the use of the
minister, the prime minister so that he
can make the best informed decisions.  It's
the same thing that we went through
between the 1940s and 1970s United
States.  You can't just focus on the one
enemy.
information and then allow
ministered policy decision.  We need
autonomous music services.  Yeah.  Yeah.
They need a lot more money and a lot
more people.  Okay.  Well, let me ask you to
send a message to the
Greeks who see us.  Your own
message from your own position, from your
own experience with what you have
done so far.  A free
message.  Look for the camera.  I
would say this.  Yes.  I hope you
understand how many Greeks are in the
diaspora, how many Greek Americans,
Greek Canadians, Greek British, Greek
Australians, Greeks all over the world
are proud of Greece and proud of the
Greek and succeed and grow.
Thank you very
much.  Ame.  Good luck with your work
that you are still doing.  I know.
Thank you very much.